LORENZO GABRIEL STIGLIANO

12 Grindlay Street, GF2, EH3 9AS, Edinburgh - +34 634583749 - stiglianolorenzo@gmail.com - ♠/LorenzoStigliano

BACKGROUND

I am a 3rd year computer science and mathematics student who is an efficient and hard worker with high standards of work output. Proficient at communicating technical ideas to both people working in technical jobs and people with little to no scientific background. Fluent in English, Spanish and Italian, both orally and written.

Research Interests: My research interests lay in mathematical modeling, statistics and applied machine learning, to impact people lives positively, in particular the applications of machine learning in medicine and robotics.

EDUCATION

The University of Edinburgh, B.Sc. Computer Science and Mathematics

Sep 2017 - Present

- · Honours level average: 88% (1st) (Pre-Honours average: 80%)
- · Selected Courses: Machine Learning, Differential Equations, Stochastic Modelling, Statistics and Probability.

King's College Madrid

Sep 2008 - Jun 2017

· A-levels: Mathematics, Further Mathematics, Physics, Spanish (A*A*AA) AS level: Economics (A)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Highly proficient in Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Java, Git, MATLAB. Experience in R, Unix.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Intern, Barclays (Glasgow, UK)

June 2019 - Present

Incoming intern at Barclays, working in the data science team.

Machine Learning Tutor, UofE School of Informatics (Edinburgh, UK)

Jan 2020 - Present

- · Responsible for tutoring the "INF2B Learning" (Machine Learning) course for 2nd year undergraduates and helped them with any quieries. Under the supervision of Dr. Hiroshi Shimodaira.
- · Skills: Leadership, communication, time management

Software Engineering Intern, Imagination Technologies (Kings Langley, UK)

Jun 2019 - Jul 2019

- · Worked in the Tools & Automation team where I created an interface (UI) and developed an emulator automation system, which released users from the tedious and repetitive job of manually interacting with hardware emulator platforms.
- · Learned how to use Flask (framework) to make a RESTful API and the SQLAlchemy toolkit for the database in our project. Gained software testing experience by creating unit tests throughout the development of the project.
- · Used Swarm software for version control, this helped me understand how to develop software in an agile environment.

Technology Spring Intern, Barclays (Glasgow, UK)

Apr 2019

- · During the internship, we got given several talks which taught us more about the financial sector and fintec.
- · This gave me a deeper understanding of what a software developer does day to day in a financial sector company.
- · We where given a group project which was to investigate the impact of VR in the financial sector. This helped me develop my team working skills as well as the opportunity to research an area that is currently growing.

Mathematics Tutor, Self-employed (Madrid, Spain)

Sep 2016 - May 2017

- · Responsible for tutoring a group of students in A-level and GCSE mathematics. Classes where done twice a week.
- · Developed teaching skills and the ability to express difficult problems in a straight forwards and understandable manner.

University of Edinburgh Programming Society

Sep 2019 - Present

Treasurer Apr 2020 - Present

· In charge of the society's finances. At the beginning of the year I helped collect funds from prospective members, and managed these funds to run academic and social events throughout the year.

· The society has over 300 members so I have to be diligent with how to manage the funds.

Python Instructor

Sep 2019 - May 2020

- · I was responsible for teaching weekly lectures on Python programming. This included actual lecturing to society members, as well as helping students with their programs and teaching members to solve more advanced problems.
- · Furthermore I created a set of exercises which were used for the beginner Python classes.

Navigation Software Developer, HYPED (Edinburgh University Hyperloop) Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

- · Responsible for designing and implementing the Edinburgh Hyperloop navigation system together with a team.
- · Communication is a vital skill in Edinburgh's Hyperloop Team as the other sub-teams must be working together to create a final product. This has helped me to develop the skills required to communicate ideas clearly and with technical language.
- · Learned the basics of C++ and how to write some code for the final software used.

Research Analyst, EUTIC (Edinburgh University Trading & Investment Club) Sep 2017 - May 2018

- · Responsible for the valuation and ratio overview of the stock we pitched. Worked with Microsoft excel and used a Relative Valuation Model to compare the stock and assessed if buying it was feasible.
- · Worked with a group of 3 members and so communication between us was vital for all of us to meet strict deadlines.
- · This gave me an insight of mathematical modeling in real life scenarios specifically in finance.

AWARDS AND PRIZES

- Prize for Maths student of the year: Awarded to 1 student for outstanding performance in maths. (2017)
- King's College Scholarship: Awarded to the top students for outstanding performance at AS Level. (2016)
- Duke of Edinburgh's International Award: Achieved both the Gold and Bronze Award. (2017)(2015)

VOLUNTEERING

• ALEPH-TEA: Helped with other volunteers at a summer camp for mentally disabled people. (2018)

• ESCALA: Assisting and helping mentally and physically disabled people in Argentina. (2015)